<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Your awesome title</title>
    <description>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</description>
    <link>http://yourdomain.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://yourdomain.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 17:24:16 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 17:24:16 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Steal Like an Artist : 10 Things Nobody Told You About Being Creative</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By: &lt;em&gt;Kleon, Austin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;How does an artist look at the world? First, you figure out what’s worth stealing, then you move on to the next thing. That’s about all there is to it. When you look at the world this way, you stop worrying about what’s “good” and what’s “bad”—there’s only stuff worth stealing, and stuff that’s not worth stealing. Everything is up for grabs. If you don’t find something worth stealing today, you might find it worth stealing tomorrow or a month or a year from now. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What a good artist understands is that nothing comes from nowhere. All creative work builds on what came before. Nothing is completely original. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Your job is to collect good ideas. The more good ideas you collect, the more you can choose from to be influenced by. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Instead, chew on one thinker—writer, artist, activist, role model—you really love. Study everything there is to know about that thinker. Then find three people that thinker loved, and find out everything about them. Repeat this as many times as you can. Climb up the tree as far as you can go. Once you build your tree, it’s time to start your own branch. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It’s not the book you start with, it’s the book that book leads you to. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You might be scared to start. That’s natural. There’s this very real thing that runs rampant in educated people. It’s called “impostor syndrome.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It means that you feel like a phony, like you’re just winging it, that you really don’t have any idea what you’re doing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I love both readings—you have to dress for the job you want, not the job you have, and you have to start doing the work you want to be doing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;First, you have to figure out who to copy. Second, you have to figure out what to copy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If all your favorite makers got together and collaborated, what would they make with you leading the crew? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The manifesto is this: Draw the art you want to see, start the business you want to run, play the music you want to hear, write the books you want to read, build the products you want to use—do the work you want to see done. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The work you do while you procrastinate is probably the work you should be doing for the rest of your life.” —Jessica Hische &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As the writer Steven Pressfield says, “It’s not that people are mean or cruel, they’re just busy.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Your brain gets too comfortable in your everyday surroundings. You need to make it uncomfortable. You need to spend some time in another land, among people that do things differently than you. Travel makes the world look new, and when the world looks new, our brains work harder. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2017/08/02/Steal-Like-an-Artist-10-Things-Nobody-Told-You-About-Being-Creative.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2017/08/02/Steal-Like-an-Artist-10-Things-Nobody-Told-You-About-Being-Creative.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Anything You Want : 40 Lessons for a New Kind of Entrepreneur</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By: &lt;em&gt;Sivers, Derek&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;delegate-or-die-the-self-employment-trap&quot;&gt;Delegate or die: The self-employment trap&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;To be a true business owner, make it so that you could leave for a year, and when you came back, your business would be doing better than when you left. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;make-it-anything-you-want&quot;&gt;Make it anything you want&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Never forget that you can make your role anything you want it to be. Anything you hate to do, someone else loves. So find that person and let her do it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-i-gave-my-company-to-charity&quot;&gt;Why I gave my company to charity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Kurt Vonnegut and Joseph Heller were at a party at a billionaire’s extravagant estate. Kurt said, “Wow! Look at this place! This guy has everything!” Joseph said, “Yes, but I have something he’ll never have. . . . Enough.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2017/08/02/Anything-You-Want-40-Lessons-for-a-New-Kind-of-Entrepreneur.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2017/08/02/Anything-You-Want-40-Lessons-for-a-New-Kind-of-Entrepreneur.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Superintelligence : Paths, Dangers, Strategies </title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By: &lt;em&gt;Bostrom, Nick&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;great-expectations&quot;&gt;Great expectations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Let an ultraintelligent machine be defined as a machine that can far surpass all the intellectual activities of any man however clever. Since the design of machines is one of these intellectual activities, an ultraintelligent machine could design even better machines; there would then unquestionably be an “intelligence explosion,” and the intelligence of man would be left far behind. Thus the first ultraintelligent machine is the last invention that man need ever make, provided that the machine is docile enough to tell us how to keep it under control. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;seasons-of-hope-and-despair&quot;&gt;Seasons of hope and despair&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Accordingly, one can view artificial intelligence as a quest to find shortcuts: ways of tractably approximating the Bayesian ideal by sacrificing some optimality or generality while preserving enough to get high performance in the actual domains of interest. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Metaphorically, we can think of a probability as sand on a large sheet of paper. The paper is partitioned into areas of various sizes, each area corresponding to one possible world, with larger areas corresponding to simpler possible worlds. Imagine also a layer of sand of even thickness spread across the entire sheet: this is our prior probability distribution. Whenever an observation is made that rules out some possible worlds, we remove the sand from the corresponding areas of the paper and redistribute it evenly over the areas that remain in play. Thus, the total amount of sand on the sheet never changes, it just gets concentrated into fewer areas as observational evidence accumulates. This is a picture of learning in its purest form. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;state-of-the-art&quot;&gt;State of the art&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;One sympathizes with John McCarthy, who lamented: “As soon as it works, no one calls it AI anymore.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The computer scientist Donald Knuth was struck that “AI has by now succeeded in doing essentially everything that requires ‘thinking’ but has failed to do most of what people and animals do ‘without thinking’—that, somehow, is much harder!” 60 Analyzing visual scenes, recognizing objects, or controlling a robot’s behavior as it interacts with a natural environment has proved challenging. Nevertheless, a fair amount of progress has been made and continues to be made, aided by steady improvements in hardware. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Now, it must be stressed that the demarcation between artificial intelligence and software in general is not sharp. Some of the applications listed above might be viewed more as generic software applications than as AI in particular—though this brings us back to McCarthy’s dictum that when something works it is no longer called AI. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The algorithm just does what it does; and unless it is a very special kind of algorithm, it does not care that we clasp our heads and gasp in dumbstruck horror at the absurd inappropriateness of its actions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;opinions-about-the-future-of-machine-intelligence&quot;&gt;Opinions about the future of machine intelligence&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;For example, Nils Nilsson has spent a long and productive career working on problems in search, planning, knowledge representation, and robotics; he has authored textbooks in artificial intelligence; and he recently completed the most comprehensive history of the field written to date. 79 When asked about arrival dates for HLMI(“human-level machine intelligence”), he offered the following opinion: 80 10% chance: 2030 50% chance: 2050 90% chance: 2100 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;vocabulary&quot;&gt;Vocabulary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lacuna - an unfilled space or interval; a gap.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2016/11/01/Superintelligence-Paths,-Dangers,-Strategies.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2016/11/01/Superintelligence-Paths,-Dangers,-Strategies.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Turning Pro: Tap Your Inner Power and Create Your Life&#39;s Work</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By: &lt;em&gt;Pressfield, Steven&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-life-as-an-amateur&quot;&gt;MY LIFE AS AN AMATEUR&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ambition, I have come to believe, is the most primal and sacred fundament of our being. To feel ambition and to act upon it is to embrace the unique calling of our souls. Not to act upon that ambition is to turn our backs on ourselves and on the reason for our existence. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;habits&quot;&gt;HABITS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The difference between an amateur and a professional is in their habits. An amateur has amateur habits. A professional has professional habits. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;art-and-addiction&quot;&gt;ART AND ADDICTION&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The amateur is an egotist. He takes the material of his personal pain and uses it to draw attention to himself. He creates a “life,” a “character,” a “personality.” The artist and the professional, on the other hand, have turned a corner in their minds. They have succeeded in stepping back from themselves. They have grown so bored with themselves and so sick of their petty bullshit that they can manipulate those elements the way a HazMat technician handles weapons-grade plutonium. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pulling-the-pin-part-two&quot;&gt;PULLING THE PIN, PART TWO&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You and I, who are artists and entrepreneurs, live a life that’s closer to natural, if you ask me. We migrate, too. We follow the Muse instead of the sun. When one crop is picked, we hit the road and move on to the next. It’s not a bad life. It’s lonely. It’s tough. It ain’t for everyone. But, like the life of a migrant on the road, it has its compensations. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-definition-of-boring&quot;&gt;THE DEFINITION OF BORING&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something that’s boring goes nowhere. It travels in a circle. It never arrives at its destination. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;addicted-to-failure&quot;&gt;ADDICTED TO FAILURE&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a glamour to failure that has been mined for centuries by starving poets, romantic suicides, and other self-defined doomed souls. This glamour inverts failure and turns it into “success.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;addicted-to-sex&quot;&gt;ADDICTED TO SEX&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I don’t see what all the fuss about sex is,” said the comedian. “It’s only friction.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-year-of-turning-pro&quot;&gt;MY YEAR OF TURNING PRO&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read all the stuff that you’re supposed to read in college but never do, or if you do, you’re not paying attention. I read Tolstoy and Dostoevsky and Turgenev. I read Cervantes and Flaubert and Stendhal and Knut Hamsun, and I read every American except Faulkner. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-definition-of-the-amateur&quot;&gt;A DEFINITION OF THE AMATEUR&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The amateur is young and dumb. He’s innocent, he’s good-hearted, he’s well-intentioned. The amateur is brave. He’s inventive and resourceful. He’s willing to take a chance. Like Luke Skywalker, the amateur harbors noble aspirations. He has dreams. He seeks liberation and enlightenment. And he’s willing, he hopes, to pay the price. The amateur is not evil or crazy. He’s not deluded. He’s not demented. The amateur is trying to learn. The amateur is you and me. What exactly is an amateur? How does an amateur view himself and the world? What qualities characterize the amateur?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-amateur-is-terrified&quot;&gt;THE AMATEUR IS TERRIFIED&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The amateur fears that if he turns pro and lives out his calling, he will have to live up to who he really is and what he is truly capable of. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-amateur-lives-by-the-opinions-of-others&quot;&gt;THE AMATEUR LIVES BY THE OPINIONS OF OTHERS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though the amateur’s identity is seated in his own ego, that ego is so weak that it cannot define itself based on its own self-evaluation. The amateur allows his worth and identity to be defined by others. The amateur craves third-party validation. The amateur is tyrannized by his imagined conception of what is expected of him. He is imprisoned by what he believes he ought to think, how he ought to look, what he ought to do, and who he ought to be. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-amateur-seeks-permission&quot;&gt;THE AMATEUR SEEKS PERMISSION&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The amateur believes that, before she can act, she must receive permission from some Omnipotent Other —a lover or spouse, a parent, a boss, a figure of authority. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-your-day-changes-when-you-turn-pro&quot;&gt;HOW YOUR DAY CHANGES WHEN YOU TURN PRO&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We now structure our hours not to flee from fear, but to confront it and overcome it. We plan our activities in order to accomplish an aim. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-professional-is-courageous&quot;&gt;A PROFESSIONAL IS COURAGEOUS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The linebacker and the Army Ranger go into action as part of a team. But the artist and the entrepreneur enter combat alone. I take my hat off to every man or woman who does this. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-professional-does-not-give-his-power-away-to-others&quot;&gt;THE PROFESSIONAL DOES NOT GIVE HIS POWER AWAY TO OTHERS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When we make someone into an icon, we give away our power. We say to ourselves (unconsciously), “This person possesses a quality I wish I possessed. Therefore I will worship this person in the hope that that quality will wear off on me, or I will acquire that quality by virtue of my proximity to this mentor/ sensei/ lover/ teacher/ hero.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The amateur is an acolyte, a groupie. The professional may seek instruction or wisdom from one who is further along in mastery than he, but he does so without surrendering his self-sovereignty. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-marine-gets-two-salaries&quot;&gt;A MARINE GETS TWO SALARIES&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we do the work for itself alone, our pursuit of a career (or a living or fame or wealth or notoriety) turns into something else, something loftier and nobler, which we may never even have thought about or aspired to at the beginning. It turns into a practice. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-professional-trusts-the-mystery&quot;&gt;THE PROFESSIONAL TRUSTS THE MYSTERY&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She asks her students to imagine a small white box. Imagine a lid on this box. Now lift the lid. What do you find inside? Sometimes students say a diamond. Sometimes a frog. Sometimes a pomegranate. The trick is, there is always something inside the box. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;take-what-the-defense-gives-you&quot;&gt;TAKE WHAT THE DEFENSE GIVES YOU&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two key tenets for days when Resistance is really strong: 1. Take what you can get and stay patient. The defense may crack late in the game. 2. Play for tomorrow. Our role on tough-nut days is to maintain our composure and keep chipping away. We’re pros. We’re not amateurs. We have patience. We can handle adversity. Tomorrow the defense will give us more, and tomorrow we’ll take it. There’s a third tenet that underlies the first two: 3. We’re in this for the long haul. Our work is a practice. One bad day is nothing to us. Ten bad days are nothing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-model-of-the-universe&quot;&gt;A MODEL OF THE UNIVERSE&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“There is a second self inside you —an inner, shadow Self. This self doesn’t care about you. It doesn’t love you. It has its own agenda, and it will kill you. It will kill you like cancer. It will kill you to achieve its agenda, which is to prevent you from actualizing your Self, from becoming who you really are. This shadow self is called, in the Kabbalistic lexicon, the yetzer hara. The yetzer hara, Steve, is what you would call Resistance.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;who-is-all-this-for&quot;&gt;WHO IS ALL THIS FOR?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will gladly shell out $24.95 or $9.99 or 99 cents on iTunes to read or see or listen to the 24-karat treasure that you have refined from your pain and your vision and your imagination. I need it. We all do. We’re struggling here in the trenches. That beauty, that wisdom, those thrills and chills, even that mindless escape on a rainy October afternoon —I want it. Put me down for it. The hero wanders. The hero suffers. The hero returns. You are that hero. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;vocabulary&quot;&gt;Vocabulary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Monomania - exaggerated or obsessive enthusiasm for or preoccupation with one thing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Surfeit - an excessive amount of something&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gnostics - relating to knowledge, especially esoteric mystical knowledge.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dint - an impression or hollow in a surface&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Proffer - hold out (something) to someone for acceptance; offer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Anathema - something or someone that one vehemently dislikes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Neophyte - a person who is new to a subject, skill, or belief&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2016/10/28/Turning-Pro.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2016/10/28/Turning-Pro.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Straight to Hell: True Tales of Deviance, Debauchery, and Billion-Dollar Deals</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By: &lt;em&gt;LeFevre, John&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-felonious-mentality&quot;&gt;A Felonious Mentality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;He was born on third base and scored on a wild pitch, but at least he can convince his friends (and himself) that he hit a triple and stole home. The ends justify the means; that’s an important concept to understand if you want to be successful on Wall Street, and is one that boarding school taught me well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Who you know is as important as what you do and how you are perceived is more important than any reality. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-parental-visit&quot;&gt;The Parental Visit&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;…in the universe of people who actually matter, investment bankers are still close to the bottom. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-wild-wild-east&quot;&gt;The Wild Wild East&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We recommend Libor +20 basis points area. “Basis points,” or “bp,” represent one hundredth of a percent, in reference to the yield, or cost of borrowing. “Area” is a term that simply means “plus or minus”; sometimes it is quantified and sometimes it is left intentionally undefined. This gives us scope to price tighter than +20 bp if the market backdrop is constructive, or slightly wider than +20 bp if the market is adverse, therefore allowing the company optimal flexibility. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-stakeout&quot;&gt;The Stakeout&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Upon seeing Justin fumble over the difference between a bid and an offer when tasked with the simple assignment &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;vocabulary&quot;&gt;Vocabulary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Abetted - encourage or assist (someone) to do something wrong, in particular, to commit a crime or other offense&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spivs - a man, typically characterized by flashy dress, who makes a living by disreputable dealings.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Teetotaler - a person who never drinks alcohol.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sycophantic - behaving or done in an obsequious way in order to gain advantage&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sanctimonious - making a show of being morally superior to other people&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Effeminate - (of a man) having or showing characteristics regarded as typical of a woman; unmanly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reticence - the quality of being reticent; reserve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2016/10/27/Straight-to-Hell.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2016/10/27/Straight-to-Hell.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Shoe Dog: A Memoir by the Creator of Nike</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By: &lt;em&gt;Knight, Phil&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;part-one&quot;&gt;Part One&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;section&quot;&gt;1962&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In every religion, it seemed, self is the obstacle, the enemy. And yet Zen declares plainly that the self doesn’t exist. Self is a mirage, a fever dream, and our stubborn belief in its reality not only wastes life, but shortens it. Self is the bald-faced lie we tell ourselves daily, and happiness requires seeing through the lie, debunking it. To study the self, said the thirteenth-century Zen master Dogen, is to forget the self. Inner voice, outer voices, it’s all the same. No dividing lines. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-1&quot;&gt;1965&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Again and again I learned that lack of equity was a leading cause of failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-2&quot;&gt;1966&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Don’t tell people how to do things, tell them what to do and let them surprise you with their results. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;But my hope was that when I failed, if I failed, I’d fail quickly, so I’d have enough time, enough years, to implement all the hard-won lessons. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-3&quot;&gt;1967&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And then Adidas threatened to sue. Adidas already had a new shoe named the “Azteca Gold,” a track spike they were planning to introduce at the same Olympics. No one had ever heard of it, but that didn’t stop Adidas from kicking up a fuss. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Who was that guy who kicked the shit out of the Aztecs?” he asked. “Cortez,” I said. He grunted. “Okay. Let’s call it the Cortez.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-4&quot;&gt;1968&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Primary principle of all accounting: Assets equal liabilities plus equity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-5&quot;&gt;1971&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Shoe dogs were people who devoted themselves wholly to the making, selling, buying, or designing of shoes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-6&quot;&gt;1973&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;He had a superb talent for underplaying the bad, and underplaying the good, for simply being in the moment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;part-two&quot;&gt;Part Two&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-7&quot;&gt;1977&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;That’s what men do when they fight. They put up walls. They pull up the drawbridge. They fill in the moat. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-8&quot;&gt;1980&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When you make something, when you improve something, when you deliver something, when you add some new thing or service to the lives of strangers, making them happier, or healthier, or safer, or better, and when you do it all crisply and efficiently, smartly, the way everything should be done but so seldom is—you’re participating more fully in the whole grand human drama. More than simply alive, you’re helping others to live more fully, and if that’s business, all right, call me a businessman. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;night&quot;&gt;Night&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I thought of that phrase, “It’s just business.” It’s never just business. It never will be. If it ever does become just business, that will mean that business is very bad. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;vocabulary&quot;&gt;Vocabulary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sinewy - consisting of or resembling sinews&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Slaking - quench or satisfy (one’s thirst)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Trattorias - an Italian restaurant serving simple food&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Languorous - the state or feeling, often pleasant, of tiredness or inertia&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Podiatry - the treatment of the feet and their ailments&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Noisome - having an extremely offensive smell&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Avuncular - of or relating to an uncle; kind and friendly toward a younger or less experienced person&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Internecine - destructive to both sides in a conflict&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fealty - a feudal tenant’s or vassal’s sworn loyalty to a lord&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quotidian - of or occurring every day; daily&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pagoda - a Hindu or Buddhist temple or sacred building, typically a many-tiered tower, in India and East Asia.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Suffused - gradually spread through or over&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Carapace - the hard upper shell of a turtle, crustacean, or arachnid.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vaunted - boast about or praise (something), especially excessively&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quixotic - exceedingly idealistic; unrealistic and impractical&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Machinations - engage in plots and intrigues; scheme&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vehement - showing strong feeling; forceful, passionate, or intense&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Portentous - done in a pompously or overly solemn manner so as to impress&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wantonly - (of a cruel or violent action) deliberate and unprovoked&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stolid - (of a person) calm, dependable, and showing little emotion or animation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Amanuensis - a literary or artistic assistant, in particular one who takes dictation or copies manuscripts.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Guile - sly or cunning intelligence&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Beguiled - charm or enchant (someone), sometimes in a deceptive way&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quell - put an end to (a rebellion or other disorder), typically by the use of force&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Debentures - an unsecured loan certificate issued by a company, backed by general credit rather than by specified assets.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Paradigmatic - of the nature of a paradigm or model&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Denouement - the final part of a play, movie, or narrative in which the strands of the plot are drawn together and matters are explained or resolved&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fetid - smelling extremely unpleasant&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Subterfuge - deceit used in order to achieve one’s goal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gabardine - a smooth, durable twill-woven cloth, typically of worsted or cotton&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ginkgo - a deciduous Chinese tree related to the conifers, with fan-shaped leaves and yellow flowers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Castigating - reprimand (someone) severely&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mohair - the long, silky hair of the angora goat&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Genuflecting - lower one’s body briefly by bending one knee to the ground, typically in worship or as a sign of respect&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Guffaw - a loud and boisterous laugh&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fusillade - a series of shots fired or missiles thrown all at the same time or in quick succession&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bacchanal - an occasion of wild and drunken revelry&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Coterie - a small group of people with shared interests or tastes, especially one that is exclusive of other people&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Opulence - great wealth or luxuriousness&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Feted - a celebration or festival&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bulwark - a defensive wall&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2016/08/29/Shoe-Dogs.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2016/08/29/Shoe-Dogs.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Obstacle Is the Way : The Timeless Art of Turning Trials into Triumph </title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By: &lt;em&gt;Holiday, Ryan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;preface&quot;&gt;Preface&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And from what we know, he truly saw each and every one of these obstacles as an opportunity to practice some virtue: patience, courage, humility, resourcefulness, reason, justice, and creativity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Not: This is not so bad. But: I can make this good. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Objective judgment, now at this very moment. Unselfish action, now at this very moment. Willing acceptance—now at this very moment—of all external events. That’s all you need. —MARCUS AURELIUS &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;part-i-perception&quot;&gt;PART I: PERCEPTION&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;recognize-your-power&quot;&gt;RECOGNIZE YOUR POWER&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;There is no good or bad without us, there is only perception. There is the event itself and the story we tell ourselves about what it means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;practice-objectivity&quot;&gt;PRACTICE OBJECTIVITY&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Take your situation and pretend it is not happening to you. Pretend it is not important, that it doesn’t matter. How much easier would it be for you to know what to do? How much more quickly and dispassionately could you size up the scenario and its options? You could write it off, greet it calmly. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;alter-your-perspective&quot;&gt;ALTER YOUR PERSPECTIVE&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Perspective is everything. That is, when you can break apart something, or look at it from some new angle, it loses its power over you. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What we can do is limit and expand our perspective to whatever will keep us calmest and most ready for the task at hand. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;is-it-up-to-you&quot;&gt;IS IT UP TO YOU?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;He understood that as a professional athlete his job was to parse the difference between the unlikely and the impossible. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;part-ii-action&quot;&gt;PART II: ACTION&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;in-praise-of-the-flank-attack&quot;&gt;IN PRAISE OF THE FLANK ATTACK&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You don’t convince people by challenging their longest and most firmly held opinions. You find common ground and work from there. Or you look for leverage to make them listen. Or you create an alterative with so much support from other people that the opposition voluntarily abandons its views and joins your camp. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;use-obstacles-against-themselves&quot;&gt;USE OBSTACLES AGAINST THEMSELVES&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Remember, a castle can be an intimidating, impenetrable fortress, or it can be turned into a prison when surrounded. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;channel-your-energy&quot;&gt;CHANNEL YOUR ENERGY&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;To be physically and mentally loose takes no talent. That’s just recklessness. (We want right action, not action period.) To be physically and mentally tight? That’s called anxiety. It doesn’t work, either. Eventually we snap. But physical looseness combined with mental restraint? That is powerful. It’s a power that drives our opponents and competitors nuts. They think we’re toying with them. It’s maddening—like we aren’t even trying, like we’ve tuned out the world. Like we’re immune to external stressors and limitations on the march toward our goals. Because we are. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;part-iii-will&quot;&gt;PART III: WILL&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;build-your-inner-citadel&quot;&gt;BUILD YOUR INNER CITADEL&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We craft our spiritual strength through physical exercise, and our physical hardiness through mental practice (mens sana in corpore)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;build-your-inner-citadel-1&quot;&gt;BUILD YOUR INNER CITADEL&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;During the good times, we strengthen ourselves and our bodies so that during the difficult times, we can depend on it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;final-thoughts-the-obstacle-becomes-the-way&quot;&gt;Final Thoughts: The Obstacle Becomes the Way&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;First, see clearly. Next, act correctly. Finally, endure and accept the world as it is. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Vires acquirit eundo (We gather strength as we go). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;See things for what they are. Do what we can. Endure and bear what we must. What blocked the path now is a path. What once impeded action advances action. The Obstacle is the Way. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;vocabulary&quot;&gt;Vocabulary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ennui - a feeling of listlessness and dissatisfaction arising from a lack of occupation or excitement.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Emulsified - make into or become an emulsion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2016/05/17/The-Obstacle-is-the-Way.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2016/05/17/The-Obstacle-is-the-Way.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kettlebell Simple &amp; Sinister</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By: &lt;em&gt;Tsatsouline, Pavel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;simple--sinister&quot;&gt;SIMPLE &amp;amp; SINISTER&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The smart and most badass tactical athletes I see on a daily basis work hard, but always leave something in the tank. They owe their lives and those of their brothers to the ability to go hard every day and not be too sore from a workout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2015/02/11/Kettlebell-Simple-and-Sinister.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2015/02/11/Kettlebell-Simple-and-Sinister.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Breaking BUD/S: How Regular Guys Can Become Navy SEALS: How Regular Guys Can Become Navy SEALs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By: &lt;em&gt;Xavier ,DH&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Compare these scores to the bare minimum scores an officer hopeful must surpass in order to be considered competitive: 500yd Swim - 9: 00 Pushups - 100 Sit-ups - 100 Pull-ups - 20 1.5mi Run - 9: 00 An officer applicant who submits these scores would be at the bottom of the stack and would need to distinguish himself further to be seriously considered. A more likely selectee would furnish scores like these: 500yd Swim - 7: 00 Pushups - 120 Sit-ups - 120 Pull-ups - 30 1.5mi Run - 8: 00 Let me be clear: If you can pass the SEAL Challenge, you are fit enough to complete BUD/ S.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2015/01/04/Breaking-BUDS.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2015/01/04/Breaking-BUDS.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
